A Finding Aid to the Maryette Charlton papers, circa 1890-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Photographic Materials, circa 1890-circa 2010; Series 14; Archival Resource Key; 7.8 Linear feet Boxes 67-74, 84-86
  - Photographs by Subject, circa 1890-2000; 14.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Winslow, Hall, Archival Resource Key (Box 72)
      - Lebanon Album, circa 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 24)
        Oversized album housed in Box 86.
      - Protest Marches, circa 1970-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 25)
    - Winslow, Hall, Archival Resource Key (Box 73)
      - Miscellaneous Photographs by Hall Winslow, 1953-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
      - Photographs of Hall Winslow, circa 1953-circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Winslow, Kirk, 1956-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 4-5)
    - Unidentified Locations, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Zen in Ryoko-In Screening at Laura Keiege Home, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Oversized Chicago Album from Box 68, Folder 11, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 84)
    - Oversized Family Album from Box 68, Folder 16, circa 1890-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 84)
    - Oversized Monticello College Album from Box 71, Folder 14, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 84)
    - Oversized Ray School of Photography Photographs from Box 72, Folder 4, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 85)
    - Oversized Winslow Hall Family Album from Box 72, Folder 23, circa 1969-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 85)
    - Oversized Winslow Hall Lebanon Album from Box 73, Folder 24, circa 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 86)
  - Personal Photographs by Maryette Charlton, 1945-1989; 14.3; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of informal photographs of friends and colleagues at various locations at home or possibly traveling. Some photographs appear to be from college. These photographs in this subseries are unrelated to film projects.
    - Personal Photographs, 1945-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 8-9)
    - Disbound Album of Friends and Colleagues, 1962-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Disbound Album of "Wanderings, Musings", 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Snapshots of and by Maryette Charlton, 1942-1984; 14.4; Archival Resource Key
    - Snapshots, 1942-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Snapshots, 1947-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Snapshots, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Snapshots, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 15-17)
    - Snapshots, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Snapshots, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Snapshots, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Snapshots, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Snapshots, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Snapshots, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Snapshots, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Snapshots, 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 5)
- Sound and Video Recordings, circa 1953-2008; Series 15; Archival Resource Key; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 74-75, 86
  This series consists of miscellaneous sound and video recordings which could not be merged with the material in other series. There are recordings of radio programs, lectures, performances, and events which Maryette Charlton attended or participated in. Folder headings in quotations are often transcriptions from the labels on the recordings. This series includes 9 videocassettes (VHS), 13 sound cassettes, 2 videodiscs (DVD), 1 sound tape reel, and 4 sounds discs (vinyl).
  - Black Kites by Jo Andres, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - "Bob Wilson (Voice)", 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - De Doute Et De Grace with Delphine Seyrig and Steve Brown, 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - "Duncan Youngerman - Musique", 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - e.e. cummings, 6 Nonlectures at Harvard, circa 1953; Archival Resource Key; 4 Sound cassettes (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - "Fairuz", circa 1970-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 11)
    Untitled cassette with list of contents starting with "Fairuz," possibly Lebanese songs.
  - Ghost Light Rough Cut, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - "Iowa" by Scotty Snyder from Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, 1998; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Kobori Speaking at Schooley's Mountain, 1971 June 6; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - "Martha's World" Trailer, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassette (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Maryette Charlton and Iris Karp, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Mimi Goese Singing "Piece of Cake", 1998; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Mimi Goese Video Flower Play, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - "Night Journey" Promotion, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - "Radio Rick", 2004; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - "Radio Rick in Heaven, Radio Rick in Hell", 2008; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - "Rhoda in Potatoland", 2008; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - "Serves You Right" Music, 1985; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - "Snow" by John Jesurun, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - White Homeland Commando by the Wooster Group, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - WNYC "The Poet's Voice" with Eileen Delahunty, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Commercial Albums, circa 1960-1980; Archival Resource Key; 4 Sound discs (vinyl) (Box 86)
    Includes "Birds of the African Rain Forests," "A Bell Ringing in the Empty Sky: Japanese Shakuhachi Music," and "China's Instrumental Heritage"
- Addition to Maryette Charlton Papers, 1951-2013; Series 16; Archival Resource Key; 3.7 Linear feet Boxes 75-79, 86
  This series is an unintegrated addition to the papers acquired in 2014. It is comprised of biographical materials, journals, correspondence, subject files, printed material and a few photographs. Personal correspondence consists of some letters written by Charlton, holiday cards, letters from artists Etel Adnan and Yasuo Fujitomi, and correspondence with her personal representative and executor Jo Andres. Found among the subject files are artists Etel Adnan, Dakota Jackson, Leon Polk Smith, Charlton's friend Lillian Kiesler, her deceased son Kirk Winslow, and miscellaneous subjects. Printed material includes books and periodicals. Also found are a few personal photographs and views of miscellaneous subjects. There is also 1 videodisc (DVD).
  Material in this series is grouped together by document type, then organized alphabetically and chronologically.
  - Biographical Materials - Address Books, 1986-circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 75, Folder 12-14)
  - Biographical Materials, Archival Resource Key (Box 76)
    - Index Cards with Addresses, circa 2000-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Appointment Calendars, 2008-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Estate Papers and Obituary, 2009-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 76)
    - Letters by Maryette Charlton, 2009-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Etel Adnan, 1982-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Jo Andres, 2005-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 6-7)
    - Letters from Yasuo Fujitomi, 1969-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Various Correspondents, circa 1970-circa 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 9-13)
    - Greeting Cards, 2006-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Holiday Cards, 2006-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 15-16)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2003-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Journals, Loose Sheets, circa 1980-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Journals, Archival Resource Key (Box 77)
    - Loose Sheets from Journals, circa 1980-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
    - Walking Journal, 1991-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Diet Journal, 1999-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Journal, 2000-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Subject Files, Archival Resource Key (Box 77)
    - Adnan, Etel, circa 1980-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 7-11)
    - Architecture, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Jackson, Dakota, 1980-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, circa 1970-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Pollock-Krasner Foundation, 1989-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Leon Polk, 1982-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Tony Reflects by Cindy Lubar Bishop, 2013; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Winslow, Kirk - Tribute, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Winslow, Kirk - Tribute Guestbook, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Subject Files, Archival Resource Key (Box 78)
    - Winslow, Kirk - Miscellaneous, 1970-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Winslow, Kirk - Photograph Album, 1955-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Printed Material - Books, 1951-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 3-7)
  - Printed Material - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 8-13)
    Oversized catalog housed in Box 86.
  - Printed Material, Archival Resource Key (Box 79)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 2001-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Periodicals, 1967-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 2-3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 4)
      Oversized material housed in Box 86.
  - Personal Photographs, 2004-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 6)
    Miscellaneous photographs of friends and family, including images of Maryette Charlton.
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalog from Box 78, Folder 8, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 86)
  - Oversized American Film Institute Publication from Box 79, Folder 4, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 86)